so it turns out i've been doing this
wrong for a long time but i found out
how to fix it i went to youtube.com and
i actually found out what they prefer
and what they recommend
to upload as a video file to their
website and so this is what i found let
me show you what i've been doing and
then how to fix it and how to upload it
correctly with great quality as well as
small file sizes
you got to just press record to get to
your export settings make sure you have
your project selected go to file and
then you can go to
share master file or what you can do is
you can come over here to the share
button
and then you can also go to master file
by clicking on that
right there so now we have this window
and this is where we're going to get
into all the information i'm going to
show you exactly what you need to do
to upload to youtube specifically to
youtube so right now on
info we can see a few things we can see
that our project is 4k which is great
that's what i wanted at we can see it's
at 23.98 frames per second
great that's what i want it as and right
here is the file size so we can see it's
a
mov we can see that it's 161 megabytes
now sometimes when you first get into
here what you'll notice is
right now i've set to h.264 but usually
it's at like an apple
pro does and this is going look it's
like twice the file size this is going
to give you
huge file sizes and it's not even
recommended to do this
for youtube it's really not necessary so
what i've been doing for the longest
time
is changing my video codec to an h.264
a lot of people do this it still works
it still goes to youtube it's
fine but this leaves you with a mov well
turns out
youtube actually wants a mp4 so i'm
going to show you how to do that
in final cut pro right now what you need
to do is go to your format
and instead of video and audio it's just
normally set to you want to go to
computer this is going to change it to a
mp4
and this is also still an h.264 file but
we're going to go to
better quality because we want the best
quality possible
now you can't really mess with this and
and change the quality
but better quality is going to give you
the best quality possible
our resolution that's fine our color
space audio format all this stuff is
fine
that's all you have to change is format
to computer make sure you're on better
quality
and this is going to give you even a
smaller file and i think why they want a
mp4 than a mov is because i believe
mov runs more natively on like apple
devices where mp4 is more of a global
standard and all the devices that are
android pc windows all that kind of
stuff are going to run
mp4 files even faster so i believe that
your
mp4 files once you upload that to
youtube is actually going to run faster
upload faster on
all devices and so that's great and
that's what you want to do especially
when youtube
is recommending that now let me show you
how to save this as a preset so you
don't have to go through all those steps
every single time you can just do it in
one click what you want to do is go back
up here to the share button and we are
actually going to add
a destination because right now when i
click on master file even though i just
change it to an mp4
i go back into my settings and it's
changed back to an h.264 mov file so we
don't want that we're going to cancel
this
we are going to add a new destination
and from here
all you really got to do is drag in
export file drag it
right there it's fine if you want it at
the very top that's great as well
when you click on it this is where you
can actually change the preset
so format again we're going to change
this to computer we're going to change
this to better quality
and then resolution i like to leave mine
at 4k
but you can always change that if you
edit in hd what you can also do here
which is cool is change the name so we
can change this to
mp4 if we want to do that and then once
you hit the close button
everything's saved you don't have to
click save you go back up here you're
going to see our
mp4 at the very top we're going to click
that we go to our settings and look
everything is saved
and we can hit next and you can see this
actually updated the resolution to match
what my timeline is at so it's going to
do that automatically which is perfect
then we're going to go to next we can
save it to our desktop or save it to
wherever we'd like
and then that is going to export for you
click on the screen to watch more final
cut pro 10
tutorials and i'll see you guys in the
next video